n chapter 10 of Black Beauty the LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna Su chapter 10 A Talk in the
Orchard Ginger and I were not of the regular tall carriage horse breed, we had
more of the racing blood in us. We stood about 15 and a half hands high; we were
therefore just as good for riding as we were for driving, and our master used to
say that he just liked either horse or man that could do but one thing; and as
he did not want to show off in London parks, he preferred a more active and
useful kind of horse. As for us, our greatest pleasure was when we were
saddled for riding party; the master on Ginger, the mistress on me, and the young
ladies on Sir Oliver and Mar legs It was so cheerful to be trotting and cantering
alt together that it always put us in high spirits. I had the best of it, for I
always carried the mistress; her weight was little, her voice was sweet, and and
her hand was so light on the rain that I was guided almost without feeling
it. Oh! if people knew what a comfort to horses a light hand is, and how it keeps
a good mouth and a good temper, they surely would not chuck, and drag, and pull
at the rain as they often do. Our mouths are so tender that where they have not
been spoiled or hardened with bad or ignorant treatment, they feel the
slightest movement of the driver's hand, and we know in an instant what is
required of us. My man M has never been spoiled, and I believe that was why the
mistress preferred me to Ginger, although her paces were certainly quite as good.
She used often to envy me, and said it was all the fault of breaking in, and the
gag bit in London, that her mouth was not so perfect as mine; and then old Sir
Oliver would say, “There, there! don't vex yourself; you have the greatest honor; a m
that can carry a tall man of our master's weight, with all your spring and
sprightly action, does not need to hold her head down because she does not carry
the lady; we horses must take things as they come, and always be contented and
willing so long as we are kindly used.” I had often wondered how it was
that Sir Oliver had such a very short tail; it was really only 6 or 7even in
long, with a tassel of hair hanging from it; and on one of our holidays in the
orchard I ventured to ask him by what accident it was that he had lost his
tail. “Accident!” he snorted with a fierce look, “it was no accident! it was a cruel,
shameful coldblooded act! When I was young I was taken to a place where these
cruel things were done; I was tied up, and made fast so that I could not stir, and
then they came and cut off my long and beautiful tail, through the flesh and
through the bone, and took it away. “How dreadful!” I exclaimed. “Dreadful, ah was dreadful; but
it was not only the pain, though that was terrible and lasted a long time; it was
not only the IND Dignity of having my best ornament taken from me, though that
was bad; but it was this, how could I ever
brush the flies off my sides and my hind legs anymore You who have tails just whisk
the flies off without thinking about it, and you can't tell what a torment it is
to have them settle upon you and sting and sting, and have nothing in the world
to lash them off with. I tell you it is a lifelong wrong, and a lifelong loss; but
thank heaven, they don't do it now.” “What did they do it for then?” said
Ginger. “For fashion!” said the old horse with a stamp of his foot; “for fashion! if
you know what that means; there was not a well-bred young horse in my time that
had not his tail docked in that shameful way, just as if the good God that made us
did not know what we wanted and what looked best.” “I suppose it is fashion that makes
them strap our heads up with those horrid bits that I was tortured with in
London,” said Ginger. “Of course it is,” said he; “to my mind, fashion is one of the
wickedest things in the world. Now look, for instance, at the way they serve dogs,
cutting off their tails to make them look plucky, and shearing up their pretty
little ears to a point to make them both look sharp for sooth I had a dear friend
once, a brown terrier Sky they called her.
She was so fond of me that she would never sleep out of my stall; she made her
bed under the manger, and there she had a litter of five as pretty little puppies
as need be; none were drowned, for they were a valuable kind, and how pleased she
was with them! and when they got their eyes open and crawled about, it was a
real pretty sight; but one day the man came and took them all way I thought he
might be afraid I should tread upon them.
But it was not so; in the evening poor Sky brought them back again, one by one
in her mouth; not the happy little things that they were, but bleeding and crying
pitifully; they had all had a piece of their tails cut off, and the soft flap of
their pretty little ears was cut quite off. How their mother licked them, and how
troubled she was, poor thing! I never forgot it. They healed in time, and they
forgot the pain, but the nice soft flap, that of course was intended to protect
the Delica part of their ears from dust and injury, was gone
forever. Why don't they cut their own children's ears into points to make them
look sharp? Why don't they cut the end off their noses to make them look plucky?
One would be just as sensible as the other. What right have they to torment and disfigure God's
creatures?” Sir Oliver, though he was so gentle, was a fiery old fellow, and what
he said was all so new to me, and so dreadful, that I found a bitter feeling
towards then rise up in my mind that I had never had
before. Of course Ginger was very much excited; she flung up her head with
flashing eyes and distended nostrils, declaring that men were both brutes and
blockheads. “Who talks about blockheads?” said Mery legs who had just come up from
the old apple tree where he had been rubbing himself against the low branch.
“Who talks about blockheads? I believe that is a bad
word.” “Bad words were made for bad things,” said Ginger, and she told him what Sir Oliver had
said. “It is all true,” said Mary legs sadly, “and I have seen that about the dogs over
and over again where I lived first; but we won't talk about it here. You know
that master, and JN and James are always good to us, and talking against men in
such a place as this doesn't seem fair or grateful, and you know there are good
masters and good greams beside ours, though of course ours are the best.”
This wise speech of good little Mery legs which we knew was quite true co us
all down, especially Sir Oliver, who was dearly fond of his master; and to turn
the subject I said, “Can anyone tell me the use of blinkers?” “No!” said Sir Oliver shortly,
“because they are no use.” “They are supposed,” said Justice, the
rone cob, in his calm way, “to prevent horses from shying and starting, and
getting so frightened as to cause accidents.” “Then what is the reason they
do not put them on riding horses; especially on ladies' horses?” said
I. “There is no reason at all,” said he quietly, “except the fashion; they say that
a horse would be so frightened to see the wheels of his own cart or carriage
coming behind him that he would be sure to run away, although of course when he
is ridden he sees them all about him if the streets are
crowded. I admit they do sometimes come too close to be pleasant, but we don't
run away; we are used to it, and understand it, and if we never had
blinkers put on we should never want them; we should see what was there, and
know what was what, and be much less frightened than by only seeing bits of
things that we can't understand. Of course there may be some
nervous horses who have been hurt or frightened when they were young, who may
be the better for them; but as I was never nervous, I can't judge.”
“I consider,” said Sir ala the blinkers are dangerous things in the night; we horses
can see much better in the dark than men can, and many an accident would never
have happened if horses might have had the full use of their
eyes. Some years ago, I remember, there was a hearse with two horses returning one
dark night, and just by Farmer Sparrow's house, where the pond is close to the
road, the wheels went too near the edge, and the hearse was overd drowned into
the water; both the horses were drowned, and the driver hardly
escaped. Of course after this accident a stout white rail was put up that might
be easily seen, but if those horses not been partly blinded, they would have
themselves kept further from the edge, and no accident would have
happened. When our master's carriage was overturned, before you came here, it was
said that if the lamp on the left side had not gone out JN would have seen the
great hole that the road makers had left; and so he might, but if old Colin had not
had blinkers on he would have seen it, lamp or no lamp, for he was far too
knowing an old horse to run into danger.
As it was, he was very much hurt, the carriage was broken, and how JN escaped nobody
knew.” “I should say,” said Ginger, curling her nostril, “that these men, who were so
wise, had better give orders that in the future all folds should be born with
their eyes set just in the middle of their foreheads, instead of on the side;
they always think they can improve upon nature and amend what God has
made.” Things were getting rather sore again, when Mery legs held up his knowing
little face and said, “I'll tell you a secret: I believe Jon does not approve of
blinkers; I heard him talking with master about it one day. The master said that 'if
horses have been used to them, it might be dangerous in some cases to leave them
off'; and John said he thought it would be a good thing if all cults were broken in
without blinkers, as was the case in some foreign countries. So let just cheer up,
and have a run to the other end of the orchard; I believe the wind has blown
down some apples, and we might just as well eat them as the
slugs merry legs could not be resisted, so we broke off our long conversation,
and got up our spirits by munching some very sweet apples which lay scattered on the
grass end of chapter